Finding Aid for Harry T. Edwards papers, ca. 1965-1980.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Harry T. Edwards papers circa 1965-1980
Edwards, Harry T.
11 linear feet
85154 Aa 2
Federal judge and former professor of law at the University of Michigan. Professional files relating to membership on board of directors of Amtrak, his work as chairman of the rules and credentials committee of the National Women's Conference, 1975, and as member of the executive committee of the Association of American Law Schools; also other files concerning his interest in labor arbitration cases, and his involvement in problems of affirmative action and minority rights at the University.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donor Number 6453.
The collection is open to research, but only after receiving written permission from the creator or his surviving spouse or children.
Judge Harry T. Edwards (born 1940) was appointed to the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit in February 1980 and served as Chief Judge from September 15, 1994, until July 15, 2001. He graduated from Cornell University in 1962 and the University of Michigan Law School in 1965.
Judge Edwards practiced law in Chicago for the firm Seyfarth, Shaw, Fairweather & Geraldson from 1965 to 1970. He then taught at the University of Michigan Law School from 1970 to 1975 and again from 1977 to 1980. In between, he taught at Harvard Law School. He also taught at the Harvard Institute for Educational Management between 1976 and 1982. He served as a member and then Chairman of the Board of Directors of AMTRAK from 1978 to 1980, and also served as a neutral labor arbitrator under a number of major collective bargaining agreements during the 1970s. He was appointed by President Jimmy Carter to the seat vacated by David L. Bazelon.
Judge Edwards has co-authored four books and published articles on labor law, higher education law, federal courts, legal education, professionalism, and judicial administration. Since joining the court, he has taught law at Harvard, Michigan, Duke, Pennsylvania, Georgetown University, and most recently, NYU Law School.
The Harry T. Edwards papers primarily document his tenure ad a board member and chairman of the board of AMTRAK. There are also files on University of Michigan Law School affairs and several labor arbitration cases in which Edward's participated. Other activities documented include his work as chairman of the rules and credentials committee of the National Women's Conference, 1975, and as member of the executive committee of the Association of American Law Schools; also other files concerning his interest in labor arbitration cases, and his involvement in problems of affirmative action and minority rights at the University.
Subjects:
Affirmative action programs--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Amtrak.; Association of American Law Schools.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan--Law School.; University of Michigan--Students.; National Women's Conference (1st: 1977: Houston, Tex.); Minority college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
African Americans--Michigan.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Biographical Information
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
- University of Michigan
  - University activities (Box 1)
  - Jewell Cobb (LSA deanship controversy) (Box 1)
  - Cheryl Clark (affirmative action case) (Box 1)
- Amtrak files
  - Board of directors minutes 1976-1979 (Box 2)
  - Board of directors minutes 1979 (Box 3)
  - Planning and finance committee records (Box 3)
  - Performance measurement reports (Box 3)
  - Retreat Conference to prepare an Amtrak statement of mission October 1978 (Box 4)
  - Executive compensation (Box 4)
  - Employee condensation (Box 4)
  - Affirmative Action (Box 4)
  - Clippings (Box 4)
  - Briefing Book (Box 4)
  - Notebook: Rail Passenger Service Act (Box 4)
  - Appointment to Board of Directors (Box 4)
  - Reorganization (Box 4)
  - General Counsel (appointment of) (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (miscellaneous) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous reports (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Selection of new officers (Box 5)
  - Board members (Box 5)
  - Sunshine laws (Box 5)
  - President's reports (Box 5)
  - Corporate bylaws (Box 5)
  - Alan Boyd (hiring) (Box 5)
  - Pass procedures (Box 5)
  - Senate approval of nomination (Box 5)
  - Senate confirmation (Box 5)
  - Car procedures (Box 5)
  - Fiscal Year 1978 Supplement Request (Box 5)
  - Five Year Corporate Plan 1978-1982 (Box 5)
  - Reistrup statement March 14, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Amtrak's deficit (Swanson) (Box 5)
  - Adams' Proposal (Route structure) (Box 5)
  - Cost simulation (Box 5)
  - DOT Route Study (Box 5)
  - DOT statement (March 1978) (Box 5)
  - Progress reports (April 1978) (Box 5)
  - Proposed legislation (Box 5)
  - Southern crescent (Box 5)
  - Fare structure (Box 5)
  - Fare policy discussion 1978 (Box 5)
  - Public Utility pricing (Box 5)
  - Harris Survey March 1978 (Box 5)
  - Train schedules (Box 5)
  - Foreign rail system (Box 5)
  - Report on information systems September 1, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Consumer Complaint Report July 1978 (Box 5)
  - NECIP equipment decision (Box 5)
  - Organization and Compensation Committee (Box 5)
  - Salary Administration Program 1971-1978 (Box 5)
  - 1978 salary plan (Box 5)
  - Salary review procedure (Box 5)
  - Superliners (Box 5)
  - Planning assumptions (Box 5)
  - Route criteria (Box 5)
  - Union terminal (Box 5)
  - Air conditioning (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
- Subject files
  - National Women's Conference 1977 (Box 6)
  - Speeches 1972-1979 (Box 6)
  - National Academy of Arbitrators (Box 7)
  - Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (Box 7)
  - American Arbitration Association (Box 7)
  - U.S. Steel and Steelworker Arbitration Board (Box 7)
  - Association of American Law Schools (Box 7)
  - Association of American Law Schools: Minority Group Section (Box 8)
  - U-M Law School business (Box 8)
  - U-M Law School business (Box 9)
  - U-M Law School student notebooks (HTE) (Box 9)
  - Harvard Law School (Box 9)
  - American Bar Association: Labor Relations Law Section (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, including clippings and other activities (Box 9)
  - Papers concerning appointment as circuit judge (Box 9)
  - Arbitration decisions (Box 10)
  - Arbitration decisions (Box 11)
    (continued)